JESS YOUNG

iess.young2@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Expertise in the intersection of internal processes, technology, and data flow in business operations. I am a scientist by training and like to dissect business problems with an analytical eye.

As a professional with international experience, I am multilingual and a clear communicator to both technical and nontechnical audiences. I have lived and worked in the US, Canada and Chile.

KNOWLEDGE

Systems design Process automation
Operations mgmt. API integration
Data analysis Project mgmt.
UI / UX Web design
Public speaking Finance

TOOLS & TECHNOLOGY

Salesforce Dell Boomi Quickbooks JSON/XML Schema Procore **Google Scripts** Quickbase HTML/CSS Git/Github AutoHotKey Javascript IFTTT/Zapier Trello FinancialForce Slack Tsheets

LANGUAGES

English $\star\star\star\star$ Spanish $\star\star\star\star$ Japanese $\star\star$ French \star

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bright Power, Inc. New York, USA

Systems and Integration Specialist: January 2019 - Present Operations Associate: January 2017 - December 2018

Engineering Operations Administrator: May 2015 – December 2016

Bright Power is an engineering consulting firm that helps buildings save energy and water. My primary role on the Technology Operations team is to build internal tools, systems and integrations to automate business processes and help our employees work more efficiently.

- Designing and building integrations for our financial, CRM, project management, construction management and time tracking platforms, primarily using Dell Boomi, in order to ensure smooth operations and flow of data between different teams.
- Implementing automation solutions using Dell Boomi, Salesforce, Google Scripts, AutoHotKey, among other tools, to minimize manual tasks and repetitive data entry across company.
- Driving organization-wide system and process improvements while interfacing with company leadership and end users from all verticals.
- Advanced Salesforce administration of 200 user org, including development in Visualforce and Apex and managing Lightning transition.

Zomato Chile, SpA. Santiago, Chile

Operations Manager: August 2014 – March 2015 Content Associate: April 2014 – August 2014

Zomato is a website and app that helps users discover new restaurants. In Santiago, Chile we built a database of 8500+ restaurants from the ground up. As Operations Manager for this fast growing start-up, I focused on growing our team and developing standardized processes.

- Heading full cycle recruitment (sales, marketing, analysts) across all verticals, from entry level to senior positions. Sourcing candidates, screening, conducting 300+ interviews, training and integration of new talent. 10 new hires.
- Implementing new expense reporting system, day-to-day bookkeeping, and working with international finance team to guarantee accountability and cost-reduction.
- Developing an HR system to ensure compliance with Chilean law including safety trainings and protocols.

EDUCATION

Northwestern University Evanston, USA

Postgraduate Researcher / Teaching Assistant: 2012 - 2013

Post-graduate studies and research in physical chemistry. The focus of my research was understanding the reactions of organic aerosol particles in the atmosphere, and their consequences in climate change. In addition I taught an Organic Chemistry laboratory course and mentored undergraduate students pursuing career in sciences.

McGill University Montreal, Canada

B.Sc. in Chemistry, First Class Honors: 2007 – 2011 (GPA: 3.64/4.00)